Guide to the Asian Students Association records, 1995-2005 UA.31.04.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Asian Students Association records
1995-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Asian Students Association
UA.31.04.0002
10.6 Linear Feet
Contains the records of the Duke University Asian Students Association from 1995-2005. Types of materials include a short history, agendas, minutes, budgets, correspondence, constitutions, resolutions, election materials, flyers, subject files, clippings, and a printed web page. Major subjects include Asian and Asian-American students, Asian and Asian-American culture, student life at Duke University, and governance of student groups. The Asian Students Association is a member of Spectrum, an intercultural coalition of student leaders and organizations at Duke University. English.
1265 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Transfer; 1997; A97-63; 2007; UA2007-0059.
Historical Note
The Asian Students Association was founded at Duke University in 1981 to serve the social, political and cultural interests of Asian and Asian-American students. The ASA hosts three annual events: Charity Ball, Lunar New Year Festival, and Heritage Month. The organization also hosts mixers with local universities, cooking classes, game nights, and brings political and educational speakers to campus. As of 2007, the Asian Students Association is active at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Contains a short history, agendas, minutes, budgets, correspondence, constitutions, resolutions, election materials, flyers, subject files, clippings, scrapbooks, and a printed web page pertaining to the general governance, social activities, and cultural activities of the Asian Students Association at Duke University. Materials range in date from 1995 to 2005
Related Material
Black Student Alliance records
University Archives, Duke University.
Diya records
University Archives, Duke University.
Spectrum records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Asian American students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Asian Americans -- North Carolina -- Durham; Asian students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Scrapbooks; Asian Americans -- Race identity; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions; Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- History; Duke University. Asian Students Association; Duke University. Spectrum
- Accession number: A97-63
  - "About Our Group", brief history and goals, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
  - Agendas and Minutes, 1996-1997, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1997-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1996-2001 (Box 1)
  - Horizons, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Intercultural Summit, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Multicultural space, funding issues, 2001 (Box 1)
  - New student welcome packet, 2000 (Box 1)
  - President's notes, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Racial harassment, subject file, 1998, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Spectrum constitution, ca. 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Task Force Proposal for the Improvement of the Asian and Asian-American Student Experience, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Web page (paper printout), 2000 (Box 1)
- Accession number: UA2007-0059, 6 boxes
  - Abercrombie and Fitch Boycott, 2002 (Box 1)
  - ASA Announcements and Emails, 2002 (Box 1)
  - ASA Presidential Task Force, 1995; 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Studies [at Duke UIniversity], 2002 (Box 1)
  - Asian Pacific American Heritage Month (Box 2)
  - Constitution and Position Descriptions (Box 2)
  - Cultural Community Reports 3rd Annual Unity Through Diversity Luncheon, March 18, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Executive Board Calendar, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Executive Board Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 2001-2005 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Events Flyers (Box 2)
  - Funding, 2002-2004 (Box 2)
  - Funding Proposals (Box 2)
  - Lunar New Year, 1999-2002 (Box 2)
  - Masquerade Ball (Charity Ball), 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Multicultural Career Conference, 2002 (Box 2)
  - President and Executive Vice President Miscellaneous Documents, 2000-2003 (Box 2)
  - President's Council Meeting, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - Unity Through Diversity: ASA Proposals, 2000-2003 (Box 2)
  - VOICES - Asian Pacific American Fall Political Series (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1986-1992 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1992-1994; 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 2000-2001 (Box 6)
  - ASA Banner (Box 7)